Brenda Beck collection from Tamil Nadu, India
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Brenda Beck collection from Tamil Nadu, India 1964-2017 1964-1966
AFC 2017/050
Beck, Brenda E. F.
approximately 22,165 items.
46 containers.
15 linear feet.
8818 manuscripts materials.
34 sound tape reels (80 hours): analog; 5 in.
43 sound cassettes: analog.
1457 photographs: film, negatives, black and white.
90 photographs: film, negatives, color.
3090 slides: color; 35 mm.
5 photographs: black and white; various sizes.
1 flash drive: 8,617 digital files; (.wav, .doc, .pdf, jpeg, tif).
10 optical discs: digital files; (.wav, .doc, .pdf, jpeg, tif); 4 3/4 in.
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of field documentation, including photographs and field recordings made by Brenda E. F. Beck during her research in the Kongu area of Tamil Nadu, India from 1964-1966. Includes audio recordings of long epic stories and shorter tales, local legends, myths, proverbs, riddles, and songs, including chants, lullabies, devotional songs, wedding songs, and funeral songs. The collection is rich in documentation of oral narrative, especially tied to temple rituals and rites of passage. Most of the material has been neatly transcribed in Tamil and translated into English. Manuscripts include extensive field notes, diaries, and maps.
Provenance
Beck, Brenda E. F.; Donation, 2017.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Materials
Brenda Beck gifted The Archives and Research Center for Ethnomusicology (ARCE), in New Delhi, with twenty-one audio cassettes of the epic tale, Annanmar Katai.
In 1971, Beck copied 5-inch reels to audiocassettes and donated them to the University of British Columbia, Vancouver.
Access and Restrictions
The Brenda Beck collection from Tamil Nadu, India is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Dr. Brenda E. F. Beck is an adjunct professor of anthropology at the University of Toronto Scarborough. She was drawn to Tamil culture after she visited the state of Tamil Nadu in Southern India when she was 14 years old and has spent her life documenting Tamil culture. In 1964, she returned to the region, to the village of Olappalayam, where she conducted her doctoral research. Her interests include South Asian mythology and Tamil folk stories. She has written several books and journal articles about the region, including, Perspectives on a regional culture: essays about the Coimbatore Area of South India edited by Brenda E. F. Beck (1979), The three twins: the telling of a South Indian folk (1982) and The Legend of Ponnivala (2013). In 1992, Beck and a Indo-Canadian animator and artist Ravichandran Arumugam translated and created an illustrated two-volume book of the epic folktale Annamaar Kadhai in Tamil and English. She created a series of graphic novels and a 13-hour, 26-episode animated series for children regarding, The Legend of Ponnivala (2013).
Beck is an advocate for the large community of Tamils living in the diaspora. In 2016, she helped develop an app to teach Tamil to students in Toronto, which has a large population of Tamils. In 2018, she founded the Brenda Beck Tamil Programming Fund and the Brenda Beck Tamil Digital Fund, which aid in investing and distributing funds for digitizing archives. With Beck's assistance, in 2019, the University of Toronto Scarborough held its first Tamil Heritage Month celebration.
Beck has received numerous awards from various Tamil community groups based in the United States, Canada, Tamil Nadu, Sri Lanka, and Malaysia. She serves as president of the Sophia Hilton Foundation of Canada, a charity that "promotes the use of storytelling at all educational levels."
Scope and Content
The collection documents two years of field research Brenda Beck conducted in the Kongunadu region of Tamil Nadu, India. The interviews were conducted in 1964-1966 as part of her doctoral research in anthropology at Somerville College, Oxford. She was assisted by Sundaram, and for a short period Professor Harold Schiffman, a linguist who recorded a few short stories for Beck. After concluding her research, Beck extended Sundaram's employment and he continued to collect stories for her.
The collection contains interviews about traditional stories, ancient oral epic folk tales, songs and proverbs, caste structures and rituals, along with in-field observations of weddings, burial ceremonies and exorcisms. It also includes hand-drawn maps and an exclusive data set of a house-to-house caste survey which captures information for each household.
The interviews capture the way of life and culture of the different caste members living in the villages. There are supporting transcripts and photographs accompanying the interviews. The transcripts are both in Tamil and English and there are spelling variations of titles throughout the collection.
Unless otherwise indicated, Beck recorded the interviews. In 2005, Beck digitized the audio recordings and created a tape inventory. In 2017 she digitized the transcripts and created a revised inventory.
Beck also digitized the black-and-white negatives between 2009 and 2017.
The flash drive: afc2017/050_cf11 contains all the files from the 10 optical discs. Some of the files have no transcript or no related physical content and these will be described in Series 9. The remaining majority of the files are digital copies of the physical items within the collection. Please note that the digital surrogates have not been matched to their original content. See Archive Index revised for more information.
Arrangement
The Brenda Beck collection from Tamil Nadu, India is organized in the following series which reflect the donor's original arrangement. Where it was possible, the transcripts were paired to the sound recordings and photographs.
Series 1: Stories 1965-1977.
Series 2: Proverbs and riddles 1969.
Series 3: Performances and songs 1965; 1975.
Series 4: Family histories 1965-1966.
Series 5: Family lineage histories-including temple rights 1966; 1969.
Series 6: Ritual and practices 1965-1969; 1976-1977.
Series 7: Fieldwork and related works 1964-1968.
Series 8: Graphic materials 1964-2017.
Series 9: Digital surrogates of sound recordings 2005
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Beck, Brenda E. F.; Beck, Brenda E. F. Social and conceptual order in Koṅku: a region of South India. 1968.; Beck, Brenda E. F. The examination of marriage ritual among selected groups in South India. 1964.
Subjects
Caste--India--Tamil Nadu.; Epic literature, Tamil.; Epic poetry, Tamil.; Festivals--India--Tamil Nadu.; Hindu chants.; Oral tradition--India--Tamil Nadu.; Rites and ceremonies--India--Tamil Nadu.; Songs, Tamil--India--Tamil Nadu.; Tales--India--Tamil Nadu.
Places
Tamil Nadu (India)--Religious life and customs.; Tamil Nadu (India)--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Diaries.; Epic songs.; Field notes.; Folk tales.; Interviews.; Photographs.; Songs.; Sound recordings.; Transcripts.
Container List
- Series 1: Stories, 1965-1977, The following transcripts and recordings have digital content that can be accessed on request on digital carrier afc2017/050_cf11.
  - Subseries 1: Major stories
    - Cutalaimata Cuvami/Cutalaicami story, June 6, 1977, Manuscript (Box-folder 1/1-3)
      Transcript.
      - Sudalaimadaswami katai (Cutalaicami) and Vallakaran story, AFC 2017/050: SR07-SR08; 2 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.; 1 cd
    - Nalamaharajan/Nallamaharajan story, August 7, 1977, Manuscript (Box-folder 1/4-7)
      - Durichandran and Nallamaharajan story, AFC 2017/050: SR10; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
        Recorded by Sundaram, 1977.
    - Arichandiren/Arichantiran story, July 7, 1977, Manuscript (Box-folder 1/8-12)
      - Arichandran Katai (Arichantiran) story, AFC 2017/050: SR09; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
    - Maduraiviran (ver. 1 and 2), April 24-25, 1976; April 29, 1977, April 29, 1976-1977; Manuscript (Box-folder 2/1-12)
      - Maduraiviran, AFC 2017/050: SR01-SR04; 4 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.
    - Maturaiviran (another version), October 29, 1965, Manuscript (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Pombaikaran Maduraiviran story, May 3, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Taiyampalayam Festival with selected short songs and stories, AFC 2017/020: SR25, SR32; 2 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.
        Recorded by Brenda Beck, February 18, 1966 and March 3-5, 1966.
    - Maturaiviran devotional song, May 3, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Lava Kusa/Lavakuca story, July 8, 1977, Manuscript (Box-folder 3/4-7)
    - Katavaraiyan Katai/Katavirayacami (ver. 1 and 2), May 12, 1966-1977, Manuscript (Box-folder 3/8 - 4/9)
      - Katavirayacami/Kattavaraya cami pattu, AFC 2017/050: SR21-SR23; 3 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.; AFC 2017/050: SR62-70; 9 sound cassettes: analog
    - Kattavirayan story (partial) sung by Mariyamaikaran, April 18, 1965, Manuscript (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Kattavirayan, AFC 2017/050: SR32; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.; AFC 2017/050: SR70; 1 sound cassette: analog
        Recorded by Brenda Beck, April 14, 1965.
    - Kattavirayan story from Kaumari Puram, June 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Katavaraiyacami story, AFC 2017/050: SR21-SR23, SR30; 4 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
        Recorded by Brenda Beck, 1966.
    - Vedan story, March 3-4, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 5/1-4)
      - Taiyampalayam Festival with selected songs and stories, Angalaaman story and Vetan Katai, AFC 2017/050: SR25, SR27; 2 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.; AFC 2017/050: SR74; 1 sound cassette: analog.
        Recorded by Brenda Beck, April 3 and May 3, 1966.
    - Manikuravan story, May 27, 1977, Manuscript (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Maduraiviran and Manikuravan story, AFC 2017/050: SR04; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
    - Angalaparamesvari, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Kovalan story, July 26-28, 1966; August 9, 1966, July 26-28, 1966 and August 9, 1966; Manuscript (Box-folder 5/7-10)
      - Kovalan story, AFC 2017/050: SR 28, SR31, SR33; 3 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.; AFC 2017/050: SR57-61; 5 sound cassettes; analog
        Recorded by Brenda Beck on July 26-28, 1966.
    - ViraaTa Parvam Villu paaTu/Virataparvam villu pattu, August 7th, 1977, Manuscript (Box-folder 5/11 - 6/1)
    - Sita's wedding story, Manuscript (Box-folder 6/2-4)
    - Chettiar story, June 15, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 6/5)
      - Chettier story, AFC 2017/050: SR30; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.; AFC 2017/050: SR73; 1 sound cassette; analog
        Recorded by Brenda Beck, June 15, 1966.
    - Nalatangal/Nallatangal story, March 4, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 6/6)
      - Taiyampalayam Festival with selected short songs and stories, AFC 2017/050: SR25; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.; AFC 2017/050: 56; 1 sound cassette: analog
        Recorded by Brenda Beck, March 4, 1966.
    - Sundara KaaNTam of Ramayana, March 4, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 6/7-9)
      - Taiyampalayam Festival with selected short songs and stories, AFC 2017/050: SR25; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
        Recorded by Brenda Beck March 3-5, 1966.
    - Vallarakkan/Vallarakan story, Manuscript (Box-folder 6/10 - 7/1)
      - Sudalaimadaswami Katai and Vallarakan stories, AFC 2017/050: SR08; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
        Recorded by Sundaram in 1977.
    - Pakkaacuuran story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/2-5)
    - Naanacavuntari/Nyanacaguntari story 1, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/6)
      - Nyanacaguntari story, AFC 2017/050: SR05-06, SR20, SR24; 4 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.
        Recorded by Beck in 1965 and completed by Sundaram in 1977. The 1977 recordings have different versions from those recorded in 1966. According to the notes accompanying the recordings AFC 2017/050: SR20 and AFC 2017/050: SR24 are incomplete stories.
    - Naanacavuntari/Nyanacaguntari story 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/7-8)
      - Nyanacaguntari story, AFC 2017/050: SR05-06, SR20, SR24; 4 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.
        Recorded by Brenda Beck in 1965 and completed by Sundaram in 1977. The 1977 recordings have different versions from those recorded in 1966. According to the notes accompanying the recordings AFC 2017/050: SR20 and AFC 2017/050: SR24 are incomplete stories.
    - Kuyavan story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Kuyavan story, AFC 2017/50: SR75; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Subseries 2: Short stories
    - A Pandya King and a Saint, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/10)
    - A Raja and his money (maybe partial), Manuscript (Box-folder 7/11)
    - A Raja's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Another Fox story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Another Raja story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Answer to question about The Cat and the fox story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/15)
    - The Astrologer's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/16)
    - The Barber's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/17)
    - The Beggar's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/18)
    - The Blind man's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/19)
    - The Cat and fox story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/20)
    - The Cat story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/21)
    - The Crane and tortoise story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/22)
    - The Crow and sparrow story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/23)
    - The Crow story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Elder brother-younger brother story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/25)
    - Four clever men, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Fox stories, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Girl with no mother, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/28)
    - Gounder story, Manuscript (Box-folder 7/29)
    - Just a story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/1)
    - The King and minister story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/2)
    - The King's story 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/3)
    - The King's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/4)
    - The Lion and the hare, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/5)
    - The Lion and the mouse, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Little saved much saved, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Mirukanda Maharishi, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Monkey boy's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Monkey story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Navitan story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Necavaali story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Palavarayan and his defeat of the Muslims, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/13)
    - The Pig and fox story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/14)
    - The Poor boy story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/15)
    - The Poor boy's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/16)
    - The Poor family story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/17)
    - The Poor man's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/18)
    - The Raja and minister's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/19)
    - The Rat who stole the stove, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/20)
    - Short story 1, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/21)
    - Short story 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Short story 3, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/23)
    - Short story 4, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/24)
    - Short story 5, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/25)
    - The Stork and turtle story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/26)
    - The Story of a King, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/27)
    - The Story of a lizard, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/28)
    - The Story of a Raja, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/29)
    - The Story of an elder and younger brother, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/30)
    - The Story of three friends, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/31)
    - The Cat and the fox, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/32)
    - The elements of a good story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/33)
    - The lame fox, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/34)
    - The Pig and the fox, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/35)
    - The Raja, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/36)
    - Two sisters without a mother, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/37)
    - Virayi Vanatti, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/38)
    - Weaver's story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/39)
  - Subseries 3: Stories about gods
    - Angaalaman, 1965-1966
      This group of Angaalamman stories can be found in AFC 2017/050: SR27. Cettiyar katai and crying songs are also included on this recording.
      - Angalamman Festival rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/40)
      - Acari Angalamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/41)
      - Angaalaalamman story 2, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/42)
      - Angaalamman and Chettiar story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/43)
      - Angaalamman, An Aacari story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/44)
        The transcript is missing pages 16-20.
      - Angaalamman affiliated kulams, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/45)
      - Angalamman associated caste groups, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/46)
      - Angalamman Festival photos, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/47)
        Transcript. Folder contains 2 black-and-white prints of the Angalamman Festival.
      - Angalamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/48)
        - Angalamman story, AFC 2017/050: SR27; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
      - Angalamman story from Pombaikaran, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/49)
        Transcript, March 3, 1965.
        - Kinship recording and short stories, AFC 2017/050: SR32; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
          Recorded by Brenda Beck assisted by Hal Schiffman, 1965-1966. See Box 8, Folder 54 for related materials.
      - Chettiar Angalamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/50)
      - Chettiar story notes, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/51)
      - Difference between written and taped Angalamman stories, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/52)
        Brenda Beck's notes on the difference between the written, spoken and taped renditions of the Angalamman stories.
      - Notes on Angaalamman story variations, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/53)
      - Pombaikarani Angalamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/54)
        Transcript. See Box 8, Folder 49 and sound recording AFC 2017/050: SR32 for related materials.
      - Goddess myth— Angalaparamesvari, Manuscript (Box-folder 8/55)
        Transcript. Story includes pages 1-21 from an unidentified source.
    - Other goddesses, 1965-1966
      - Batirakaliamman story from Kanthapurana, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/1)
      - Batirakaliammani story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Kamakshiamman poems, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Kuttiamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/4)
      - Nattakkataiyur Mariyamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Vankalamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Vankalamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Gods
      - Aiyanar story 1, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Aiyanar story 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/9)
      - Karupanacaami story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Kuppanacami of Muttur, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/11)
        Transcript. Story from the temple Priest Muttin, October 26, 1965.
      - Muttur Karupanasami story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/12)
      - Siva's dance contest, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/13)
        Transcript, September 1980.
      - Story of Nadar Kula devam at Palaiyakottai, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/14)
      - Story of Vettuva Karupanasami (Maataari kula devam), Manuscript (Box-folder 9/15)
      - Muttur Karupanasami Drama of the 500 puranas, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Mariyamman
      Recordings of the Mariyamman Festival, found in AFC 2017/050: SR29.
      - Mariyamman story for Cankarantampalayam, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/17)
      - Mariyamman comes to Gannapuram, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/18)
      - Mariyamman Festival rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/19)
      - Mariyamman invocation to attend the festival, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/20)
        Transcript of the invocation of invitation to the gods to preside over or attend the five pot dance of Mariamman during her festival. Information gathered from Sundaram notes, February 19th, 1966.
        - Short stories, AFC 2017/050: SR29; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
          Recorded by Brenda Beck, April 15, 1965.
      - Mariyamman pongal toranam tying-1, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/21)
      - Mariyamman pongal toranam tying-2 maps, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/22)
      - Mariyamman praise song, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/23)
      - Mariyamman story 1, February 14, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/24)
        Transcript. See Box 9, Folder 28 for related materials.
      - Mariyamman story 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/25)
        Transcript. See Box 9, Folder 29 for related materials.
      - Mariyamman's 1,000 eyes story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/26)
        Transcript of story told by Papamman, February 2, 1966. See Box 9, Folder 40 for related materials.
      - Mariyamman Festival, traditional payments, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/27)
        Folder contains the receipt of the traditional payment at Mariamman Temple. The payment is due at the Sitarai Festival according to Sundaram's records February 19, 1966.
    - Myths about divine beings and temple origins
      - Maariyamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/28)
        Transcript of Gannapathi pandaram, Kangayampalayam (now Vellakoil), February 14, 1966. See Box 9, Folder 24 for related materials.
      - Maariyamman story 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/29)
        Transcript of Kannapath Pandaram(Vellakoil). Recorded first week, October, 1965. See Box 9, Folder 25 for related materials. See also Box 9, Folder 40
      - Maariyamman song, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/30)
      - How Maariyamman came to Gannapuram, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/31)
      - How Maariyamman came to Natakaataiyur, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/32)
      - Cankarantaampaalaiyam Kottai Mariyamman story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/33)
      - Maariyamman's 1,000 eyes, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/34)
        Transcript. See Box 9, Folder 26 for related materials.
      - Kannimar Karupanacami story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/35)
        - Taiyampalayam Festival with selected short stories and songs, AFC 2017/050: SR25; 1 sound tape reel; analog; 5 in.
      - Karuppanacami story-song, March 5th, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/36)
        - Taiyampalayam Festival with selected short stories and songs, AFC 2017/050: SR25; 1 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.
      - Vettuva Karuppanacami story 1 and 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/37)
      - Murugan story 1, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/38)
      - Murugan story 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/39)
      - Murugan story 3, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/40)
      - Olappalayam and Gannapuram origin story, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/41)
        Transcript, February 14, 1966.
      - Poem for Krishna puja, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/42)
        Includes poem for Krishna puja by Pertasi Masam from Sundaram notes.
      - Poem for Murugan puja, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/43)
        Includes poem for Murngan puja by Panganni Masam from Sundaram's notes, February 19, 1966.
      - Pombaikaran, Maduraiviran song, March 5, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/44)
        Transcript, March 5, 1966.
        - Taiyampalayam Festival with selected short stories and songs, AFC 2017/050: SR25; 1 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.
          Recorded by Brenda Beck, March 3, 1966.
- Series 2: Proverbs and riddles, 1969, The following transcripts and recordings have digital content that can be accessed on request on digital carrier afc2017/050_cf11.
  - Proverbs, April 24th, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/45)
  - Riddles 1, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/46)
  - Riddles 2, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/47)
  - Riddles 3, Manuscript (Box-folder 9/48)
- Series 3: Performances and songs, 1965; 1975, The following transcripts and recordings have digital content that can be accessed on request on digital carrier afc2017/050_cf11.
  - Ponnivala Annanmar story texts, original, Manuscript (Box-folder 10/1 - 12/5)
    - Annanmar story, AFC 2017/050: SR11-SR20, SR24; 11 sound tape reels; analog; 5 in.